这只小猫叫手套  这只是费修
This kitty is Mittens. This one is Fitzhugh.
然后住在猫公寓的小公猫是金吉
And this little guy in the cat condo is Jinkies.
好多猫噢  裘琳
That's a lot of cats,Jo Lynn.
你是单身吧
Single,are you?
钱德勒·宾
Chandler Bing.
为什么是你自己接电话呢
How come you're answering your own phone?
你的疯狂助理去哪了
Where's your crazy assistant?
什么事  乔伊
What's up,Joe?
有什么事是我们一直想一起做的
Ok, What have we always wanted to do together?
帮彼此编辫子  然后在海边骑马吗
Braid each other's hair and ride horseback on the beach?
不不不  你明晚回家时
No. No. No. When you get home tomorrow night..
你跟我要去看奇才队对尼克斯队球赛
you and I are gonna be at the WizardsKnicks game,
场边座位
courtside!
场边座位  我的天啊  是啊
Courtside? Oh,my God!  Yeah!
或许迈克尔·乔丹会扑过来抢球
Maybe Michael Jordan will dive for the ball
然后用他的膝盖撞断我的下巴
and break my jaw with his knee!
真是太酷了  我来告诉莫妮卡
That is so cool. I'll let Monica know.
喂  乔伊刚打电话来
Hello?  Joey just called.
他帮我买到了
He's got courtside
明晚尼克斯队比赛的场边座位
Knicks tickets for him and me tomorrow night.
是吗
Really?
但是明晚是我唯一
But tomorrow night's the only night
不用上班的晚上
I get off from the restaurant.
如果你去看球赛
If you go to the game,
我们会有一星期没有办法在一起
we won't have a night together for another week.
但是亲爱的  那是场边座位
But honey,it's courtside!
啦啦队就在正前
The cheerleaders will be right in..
这样可不能说服你
That's not the way to convince you.
我不想要成为那种老婆  老是说
I don't wanna be one of those wives that says:
"你不能去看球赛  你要陪我"
"You can't go to the game. You have to spend time with me."
所以如果你自己能够意识到
So if you could just realize it on your own..
我知道  你说的对
I know. You're right.
我也想要见到你
I wanna see you too.
我得要想想怎么告诉乔伊
I gotta figure out a way to tell Joey.
他是满心期待着
He's looking forward to this.
告诉他你很久没有见到老婆了
Tell him you haven't seen your wife in a long time.
告诉他长距离关系
Tell him that having a longdistance relationship
是很难维系的
is really difficult.
告诉他我们有限的相处时间
Tell him that what little time we have together
是很宝贵的
is precious.
我会想想别的
I'll think of something.
《老友记》  第九季 第9集  瑞秋的电话号码
Friends S09E09 The One With Rachel's Phone Number
你看起来
You look..
我是说  真的  这件礼服
I mean,it's just.. That dress..
我希望你要说出口的是好的评价
Well,I hope the ends of these sentences are good.
是好的  只是我很久没有
They're good. It's just been a while since
看到你这样打扮
I've seen you like this.
你产后恢复的真好
You clean up good.
真的吗  噢  谢谢你
Really? Well,thank you.
好了  别再这样看着我了
Okay,stop looking at me like that.
上次这样的时候  就那样了
Last time that happened,that happened.
对  是的
Right,right.
你开心可以第一次离开艾玛出去玩吗
So are you excited about your first night away from Emma?
是啊  菲比跟我会玩的很开心的
Yeah,yeah. Phoebe and l are gonna have so much fun.
谢谢你帮忙看小孩  不用客气
Thank you for watching the baby.  It's fine.
事实上  我有邀请麦克过来
Actually,I invited Mike over.
菲比的麦克吗  是啊
Phoebe's Mike?  Yeah.
我不知道你们很熟  我们没有
I didn't know you hung out.  We don't..
但是我想要多了解他
but I'd like to get to know him.
或许用点晚餐  喝点酒  然后聊聊天
Maybe have a little dinner,drinks,conversation.
太有爱了 罗斯跟麦克的第一次约会
That's so cute. Ross and Mike's first date.
那会不会很尴尬  你们要聊些什么呢
Will that be awkward? What are you gonna talk about?
我不知道  但是你知道的
I don't know. But you know,
我们有许多共同点  明白吗
we have a lot in common,you know?
他会弹钢琴  我在大学弹过电子琴
He plays piano. I played keyboards in college.
他离过婚  我在那方面也有些经验
He's been divorced. I have some experience in that area.
请进  嗨
Yeah?  Hi!
果真是女人之夜
Girl's night out indeed.
我想艾玛今晚可能已经睡了
So I think Emma is probably down for the night..
但是如果你们需要
but if you need anything..
瑞秋  我们会没事的
Rach, We'll be fine.
祝你们玩得愉快  好的  你们也是
You go have fun.  Okay,you too.
谢谢  还有我希望你可以"上垒"
Thanks.  And I hope you score.
好的  再见  再见
Okay. Bye.  Bye.
欢迎造访
So,welcome.
我有啤酒  我有瓶装母乳
I got beer.  I got bottled breast milk.
我看我们先喝啤酒好了 好的
Why don't we start with the beer.  Okay.
菲比告诉我你会弹钢琴  是啊
So Phoebe tells me you play piano.  Yeah.
我在大学的时候也会弹电子琴
You know,I used to play keyboards in college.
你这里有吗
Do you have one here?
没有
No.
好吧
Okay.
你知道的  我离过婚
You know,I'm divorced.
菲比  菲比说你  你也离过婚
Phoebe.. Phoebe says you're.. You've been divorced?
是的  是啊
Yeah,yeah.
很抱歉  我真的不太喜欢谈那事
Yeah,I'm sorry. I don't really like to talk about it.
没关系  我们可以聊别的
That's okay. We'll talk about something else.
你是古生物学家  是吗  是啊
So you're a paleontologist,right?  Yeah.
我表哥也是古生物学家
My cousin's a paleontologist.
他跟我可能会有较多话题可以聊
Well,he and I would probably have a lot to talk about.
欢迎回家  瞧瞧你
Welcome home.  Well,look at you.
是啊  觉得怎样呢
Yeah. What do you think?
看起来很棒  只不过
Well,it looks great. It's just..
我里面穿的也跟你一样  所以
I'm wearing the same thing underneath,so..
你知道我的意思吗
You see what I mean?
嘿  为什么你的门是锁着的
Hey! How come your door's locked?
等一下  不不不
Just a second!  No,no,no!
不能让乔伊看到我在这里
Joey can't know I'm here.
为什么不能
Why not?
因为我不知道怎么告诉他
Because I didn't know how to tell him that
我不能去看尼克斯队的球赛
I couldn't go to the Knicks game..
所以我跟他说我要留在塔尔萨
so I told him I had to stay in Tulsa.
所以你跟他说谎
So you lied to him?
说谎比费口舌解释要好太多了
It's always better to lie than to have the complicated discussion.
除了跟你之外
Except with you.
嘿  开门  是怎么回事
Hey,open the door! What's going on?
你在干么  嗨
What are you..?  Hi.
你为什么穿成这样呢
Why are you dressed like that?
因为钱德勒几天以后就要回来了
Because Chandler's gonna be home in a couple of days..
所以我觉得自己可以...
so I thought I would just,
先  练习一下妩媚的技巧
you know,practice the art of seduction.
我刚刚好像听到有男人的声音
I thought I heard a man's voice before.
没有  我只是在扮钱德勒说话
No,I was just doing Chandler's side of the conversation.
你知道的  就像是
You know,like,
"嗨  我看起来如何"
"Hi,how do I look?"
"真性感  我还能比现在更性奋吗"
"Really sexy. Could I be any more turned on?"
明白吗
You know?
好的  等一下
Okay. Wait a minute.
为什么有两杯酒呢
Why are there two glasses of wine out?
因为有一杯是要给你的
Because one of them is for you!
干杯  好了  再见
Cheers! Okay,byebye.
真有意思
You know,it's funny.
我自己也一直在练习勾引的技巧
I've been practicing the art of seduction myself.
你最好继续加强练习  是噢
You might wanna keep practicing.  Yeah.
是乔伊  什么
It's Joey.  What?
嘿  乔伊  老兄  快回家
Hey,Joe.  Dude,come home!
什么  为什么  快回家
What? Why?  Come home!
听着  我不行  是怎么回事
Look,I can't. What's going on?
我不知道要怎么开口
I don't know how to tell you this,
但是我觉得莫妮卡有外遇
but I think Monica's cheating on you!
早就告诉过你  你不应该娶一个
I told you,you shouldn't have married
比你性感那么多的人
someone hotter than you!
如果你没有办法回来处理这事
If you can't deal with this,
那我去处理
then I'm gonna.
不  我刚听到他的声音了
No!  I just heard him!
你现在有听到他的声音吗
Can you hear him now?
没有  好了  我要进去了
No. All right,I'm going in.
不  等等  我又听到他了
No,wait!  I heard him again!
好了  你就待在那里别动
All right,just stay there.
我要回家了
I'm coming home.
很好  等你回来的时候见
Ok, great, I'll see you when you get here.
我会在门外守着  以免他逃了
I'll wait out in the hall in case he comes out.
有那个必要吗
Is that really necessary?
当然  你也会为我这样做的
Absolutely. You'd do it for me.
不是说你会有机会那样做
Not that you ever have to,
因为我知道要如何满足我的女人
because I know how to keep my women satisfied.
披萨不是早就该到了吗
Shouldn't the pizza be here by now?
我是说  他们说不用30分钟就会到
I mean,they said 30 minutes or less.
已经多久了呢
Well,how long has it been?
11分钟
Eleven minutes.
现在是12分钟
And now 12.
你喜欢这啤酒吗  是的  我喜欢
So you like the beer?  I do. I do.
不过  这事实上是窖藏啤酒
Although,it's actually a lager.
那普通啤酒跟窖藏啤酒有什么不同呢
What's the difference between beer and lager?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们可以查一查
We could look it up.
真是越来越失控了
Things are about to get wild.
天啊  还记得以前的女生之夜吗
Oh,God,remember the girls' nights we used to have..
坐在一起讨论你跟罗斯的事吗
sitting around talking about you and Ross?
噢  天啊  感觉好像是上辈子的事
Oh,God! It seems like forever ago.
我知道
I know.
那  你跟罗斯是怎样了呢
So,what's going on with you and Ross?
噢  我不知道
Well,I don't know.
我是说  好长时间都无事发生
I mean,for a long time,nothing.
但是  事实上  就在你来接我之前
But you know,actually,right before you picked me up..
罗斯跟我有个小小的"火花"
Ross and I had a little thing.
噢  我的天  我最爱小火花
Oh,my God! I love things!
发生什么事
What happened?
他先是告诉我  他喜欢我的样子
Well,first he told me he liked how I looked.
然后我们来了个小小的
And then we had a little..
眼神接触
eye contact.
Eye contact?
我希望你们有用避孕措施
I hope you were using protection.
打扰一下
Excuse me,
这些是吧台最后那两位先生请的
these are from the two gentlemen at the end of the bar.
我们应该回请他们什么的吗
Should we send them something back?
我们请他们吃土豆泥好了
Let's send them mashed potatoes!
不  等等  别那么做
No,wait! Don't do that!
那样他们就会认为他们可以过来
That'll make them think they can come over.
所以呢  过来又如何呢
So,what if they do?
我们不是来这里钓男人的
We're not here to meet guys.
你有男友  我有小孩还有罗斯
You have a boyfriend. I have a baby and a Ross.
是啊  但又不会发生什么事
Yeah,but nothing has to happen.
只是玩玩而已
We're just having fun.
不是每件事都得发展到眼神接触地步的
You know,not everything has to go as far as eye contact.
钱德勒  你得告诉乔伊
Chandler,you have to tell Joey
你不在塔尔萨
you're not in Tulsa.
让他认为是你在欺骗我
Isn't it better for him to think you're cheating on me..
总比他认为我在欺骗他好吧
than for him to think I'm cheating on him?
我可听说过
I heard it.
我不想让他误会我有外遇
I don't want him to think I'm having an affair.
好了  我有个计划
All right,I've got a plan.
我会从防火梯爬下去
I'll go down the fire escape..
所有"完美计划"都是从
Because all good plans start with,
"我会从防火梯爬下去"开始的
"I'll go down the fire escape."
听我说完  女人
Hear me out,woman!
我会从防火梯爬下去  然后等着
I'll go down the fire escape and I'll wait for a while.
然后我从楼梯走上来
Then when I come up the stairs
就像是我刚从塔尔萨回来一样
it'll be like I just got back from Tulsa.
然后乔伊跟我进屋
Joey and I will come in and see
看到这里根本没有男人
that there's no guy in here.
你难道不怕乔伊会识破吗
Aren't you afraid that Joey's gonna figure all this out?
我可听说过
I heard it.
我要等一下
I'm just gonna wait for a little while.
可怕的鸽子又回来了吗
The scary pigeon's back?
超大的
It's huge.
天啊  我不敢相信你住在那栋公寓
Oh, my god. I can't believe you live in that building.
我奶奶也住在那栋公寓
My grandmother lives in that building!
艾达·格林  完全不懂尊重个人空间
Ida Greene? No sense of personal space..
闻起来像鸡  看起来像马铃薯
kind of smells like chicken,looks like a potato.
"洋芋"是你奶奶
"Spuds" is your grandmother?
那就是我"阿奶"
That's my bubbe!
我们要再去几个派对
So we're on our way to a couple of parties.
或许可以把你们的号码给我们
Maybe we could get your numbers
如果遇到好玩的  打电话给你们
and call if we find something fun?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry,
我们并不期望
we weren't really looking for anything
和你们会有艳遇发生
to happen with you guys.
我有男朋友了
I have a boyfriend.
好的  没关系
All right.  It's no big deal.
所以她有男朋友  那你的情形是怎样呢
So she has a boyfriend. What is your situation?
有点复杂  我并没有男朋友  但是
Well,it's complicated. I don't actually have a boyfriend,but..
那我可以跟你要电话号码吗
Then can I have your number?
我很抱歉  不行
I'm sorry,no.
好的
Okay.
当然可以
Oh,sure!
噢  天啊  你给他的电话是真的
Oh,my God,you're giving your real number!
好的  谢谢  我今晚会打给你
Okay,thanks. I'll give you a call later tonight.
太好了 再见
Great.  Bye.
再见
Bye.
那真的太棒了
So that's great.
你  比尔  罗斯  艾玛
You,Bill,Ross and Emma
会很幸福地生活在一起
are gonna be so happy together.
你在想什么呢
What were you thinking?
我不知道  他很可爱
I don't know. He was cute,
又喜欢我  我冲动之下就给他了
and he liked me. It was an impulse.
那罗斯怎么办  你们的小火花呢
But what about Ross? What about your moment?
你不想跟他谈谈吗  不想
Don't you wanna talk to him?  No.
不想  因为我非常清楚
No,because I know exactly
谈话的结果会是怎样
how the conversation's gonna go.
"嘿  罗斯
"Hey,Ross,you know,
我觉得我们刚刚有点小火花"
I think we had a moment before."
"是啊  我也这么认为"
"Yeah. Me too."
"但是我不太确定
"Well,but I'm not sure
我是不是想再更进一步"
I really want to do anything about it."
"是啊  我也不确定"
"Yeah. Me neither."
我们是不是就住在一起
"Should we just live together..
然后不要告诉彼此  我们互相的感受
and not tell each other how we're feeling?"
"是啊  我没意见"
"Yeah,that works for me."
是啊  我懂你的意思
Yeah,I see what you mean.
对了  你模仿罗斯真像
By the way,nice Ross imitation.
但你模仿的瑞秋不够爱发牢骚
Your Rachel wasn't whiny enough.
嗯嘿  好多了
Well.. Hey!  Better.
重点是我或许应该停止等待
The point is maybe I should just stop waiting around
跟罗斯之间的小火花
for moments with Ross.
我是说  我要继续过我自己的生活了
You know? I should just move on with my life.
真的  你要放弃罗斯了
So really,you're moving on from Ross?
我不知道  我得现在就做决定吗
I don't know. Do I have to decide right now?
你好像已经做了
You kind of just did.
那男的今晚会打电话给你
That guy is gonna call you tonight.
罗斯会接起电话
Ross will pick up the phone,
那传达的讯息已经很明显了
and that's a pretty clear message.
噢  天啊  罗斯
Oh,my God,Ross!
罗斯会接起电话
Ross is gonna pick up the phone.
我得拿回我的电话号码
I have to get my number back.
噢  天啊  他走了
Oh,my God,he's gone!
"我得拿回我的电话号码
"Oh,I have to get my number back!
噢  天啊  他走了"模仿的真棒
Oh,my God! He's gone!" Dead on.
我想我该走了  这么快吗
You know,I'm gonna take off.  So soon?
是啊  好的
Yeah.  Okay.
嗯  谢谢你带啤酒过来
Well,thanks.. Thanks for the beer.
你是说窖藏啤酒吧
You mean lager?
是啊  快乐时光
Yeah. Good times.
喂  嘿  麦克  是我
Hello?  Hey,Mike,it's me.
听着  罗斯在你旁边吗
Listen,is.. Is Ross near you?
不在  我刚走
No,I just left.
你得再回去
Well,you have to go back in.
什么  回去  回到时光暂停之地吗
What? Go back? To the land where time stands still?
我很抱歉  亲爱的  但是
I'm so sorry,honey,but..
瑞秋把自己的号码给了一个男人
Okay,Rachel gave this guy her number..
她不希望罗斯去接电话
and she doesn't want Ross to answer the phone.
所以你必须拦截他所有的电话
So you have to intercept all his calls.
我不能那样做
I can't do that!
他说他不能那样做  电话给我
He says he can't do that.  Give me the phone.
麦克  听着
Hi,Mike. Hi,listen,
我知道这个要求很过分
I know that this is a lot to ask,
但是你知道吗  如果你照做
but you know what? If you do this,
菲比会做一切你想要她做的事
Phoebe will do anything you want.
真的  我说得是很下流的事
Seriously,I'm talking dirty stuff.
喂
Hello?
嗨  我替她道歉
Hi,I'm sorry about her.
但事实上  关于下流的事  她说的没错
But actually,she wasn't wrong about the dirty stuff.
好了  我照做
All right,I'll do it.
但说真的  能有多下流呢
But really,how much dirtier can it get?
噢  麦克
Oh,Mike.
再见
Bye.
嘿  老兄
Hey,buddy.
我可以回来吗  为什么
Can I come back in?  Why?
我只是在想  我们
Well,I was just thinking about
还有很多东西可以聊
how much more we have to talk about.
但是你都走了
But you left.
你倒是挺快的
That didn't take long.
你不是说塔尔萨到这里要飞三小时吗
I thought you said Tulsa was,like,a threehour flight?
你忘了把时差算进去了
Well,you're forgetting about the time difference.
钱德勒  你回来了
Chandler,you're home!
没错  你老公回来了
That's right! Your husband's home!
所以现在性爱派对可以停止了
So now the sex can stop!
你在说什么
What are you saying?
乔伊说你跟另一个男人在一起
Joey said you're here with another man!
这里根本没有男人
There's no man in here!
你怎么敢这样诬赖我
How dare you accuse me of that!
好吧  那或许你不介意
All right. Then maybe you won't mind
我和我的朋友到处看看
if me and my friend take a look around.
他在做什么
What's he doing?
我把枕头做成人形在床上
I arranged some pillows on the bed to look like a guy.
卧室没有人
Bedroom's clear.
不过你们可能需要换新的枕头了
Although you might need some new pillows.
好了  那我去检查客房
All right,well,I'll check the guest room.
我为什么闻到男人的古龙水味
Why do I smell men's cologne?
我想那是你的味道
I think that's you.
噢  对噢
Oh,yeah.
我刚刚才用杂志磨擦到自己身上
I rubbed a magazine on myself earlier.
里面没有人  乔伊
There's nobody here,Joe.
我想也没有
I guess not.
我不敢相信你认为我会有外遇
I can't believe you thought I was cheating.
你要对我道歉
You owe me an apology.
你说的对  莫妮卡  我很抱歉
You're right. Monica, I'm so sorry.
你是无心之失
It's an honest mistake.
可能发生在任何人身上的  再见
It could happen to anybody. See you.
等一下  等一下
Wait a minute,wait a minute.
如果你才刚从塔尔萨回来
If you just got back from Tulsa,
你的行李怎么会比你先到
how did your suitcase beat you here?
我从防火梯爬了下去
I climbed down the fire escape,
你就不能把这个藏到衣橱里吗
and you can't put that in the closet?
所以  除了发酵过程不同之外
So,with the exception of the fermentation process..
啤酒跟麦酒基本上是相同的东西
beer and ale are basically the same thing.
真引人入胜  不是吗
Fascinating,isn't it?
或许你应该查一下"引人入胜"的意思
Maybe you should look up "fascinating."
我来接
I'll get it!
嗨  罗斯家  我是麦克
Hello? Ross' place. Mike speaking.
要找你的
It's for you.
我不懂刚刚发生的事
I don't understand what just happened here.
是怎么回事
What's going on?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我跟你说我会留在塔尔萨是因为
I told you I was in Tulsa because
今晚我想要跟莫妮卡在一起
I wanted to spend the night with Monica..
我说不清  我以为你会不谅解
and I didn't know.. I didn't think you'd understand.
你以为我笨到会不谅解
You think I'm too dumb to understand
老公想要跟老婆在一起吗
a husband needs to be with his wife?
你以为我就像
You think I'm,like..
乔伊  怎样
Joey?  Yeah.
我不知道该说什么
I don't know what to say.
我们不应该欺骗你的
We shouldn't have lied to you.
我觉得很难过
I feel so bad.
我能做什么补偿你吗
Is there anything I can do to make it up to you?
你可以跟我一起去看球赛
You could go to the game with me.
虽然你说了你不行
Even though you said you couldn't.
但是你欺骗我  耍弄我
But then you lied to me and tricked me
然后又害我头肿了一包
and gave me a bump on the head.
我很抱歉  那是我唯一无法做到的
I'm sorry,that's the one thing I can't do.
我答应莫妮卡要跟她在一起了
I promised I'd be with Monica.
好吧
All right.
你去吧  什么
You can go.  What?
你应该去看球赛
You should go to the game.
没关系  我要你去
It's okay. I want you to.
真的  你没关系吗
Really? You gonna be okay?
是的  我没关系
Yeah,I'll be fine.
你知道的  或许我可以留在家里
You know,maybe I'll stay here
然后练习一下勾引的技巧
and practice the art of seduction.
你要换上运动服  然后打扫吧
You're gonna put sweats on and clean, aren't you?
一定会很性感撩人
It's gonna be so hot!
再见 再见
Bye.  Bye.
谢了
Thanks.
你的门票
Here's your ticket.
谢了  嘿  听着
Thanks. Hey,listen..
我再也不会对你说谎了  好吗
I'm never gonna lie to you again,okay?
而且我要你知道
And I want you to know
没有人认为你是愚蠢的
that nobody thinks you're stupid.
谢了  老兄
Thanks,man.
你要去哪
Where you going?
球赛是明晚  乔伊
Game's tomorrow night,Joe.
真高兴你们回来了
So glad you're back!
那你们做了些什么呢
So,what did you guys do?
你知道的  我们喝了一些啤酒
You know,we just drank some beer.
麦克示范了正常社交礼仪的界线在哪
Mike played with the boundaries of normal social conduct.
真的  我的确如此
It's true,I did.
好了  再见  好的
Well,goodbye.  Okay.
再见  真好玩  菲比
Bye. That was fun,Phoebe.
我知道  真好玩
I know. It was fun.
再见
See you,guys.
锁门  锁门  快点
Lock the door! Lock the door,seriously.
糟了  我忘记给菲比酒钱了
Shoot,I forgot to pay Phoebe for the drinks.
等等  等一下  不好意思
Wait,wait. Wait,sorry.
他有打来吗  那个男的有打来吗
Did he call? Did that guy call?
没有  只有他妈打来
No,just his mom.
在八点半左右吗
Around 8:30?
是的 然后九点再一通吗
Yeah.  Then again at 9:00?
喂
Hello?
她现在不在  要留言吗
No,she's not here right now. Can I take a message?
酒吧认识的比尔
Bill from the bar?
好的  酒吧认识的比尔
Okay,Bill from the bar,
我会把你的号码给她的
I'll make sure she gets your number.
好玩吗
So.. So how was it?
你们  你们玩的开心吗
Did you guys..? You guys have a good time?
我们玩的很开心  出去玩真是快乐
We had so much fun. It felt so good to be out.
瑞秋
Rach?
什么事
Yeah?
没事
Never mind.
嗨  你们  嘿
Hey,you guys.  Hey!
马上回来  我要去上厕所
I'll be right back. I gotta go to the bathroom.
黑啤酒也是啤酒的一种
Stout. That's a kind of beer.